Kevin Adrián Rodríguez Ruiz

Software Engineer

About me

Chemical engineer and master's student in computing with more than four years of experience in software development.

Experience with Web Development, Javascript scripting, Python, Java, Spring Framework, Amazon Web Services (10+products) and VSTO Add-ins.

I am excited about making things easier to other engineers and scientists.

Interests

Web development, Data analysis, Phenomena Modelling and Optimization.

Learning new engineering/science topics.

Languages

Spanish (native) English (fluent) French (basic)

Contact

Bogotá, Colombia. 111156 (+57 1) 6698229 (+57) 3057052399 karodriguezr@unal.edu.co LinkedIn profile GitHub public repositories

SKILLS

Technical Skills: Java, Javascript, Html, Node.js, Python, Django Framework, React.js, Amazon Web Services, VBA, Spring Framework, Git, VSTO Add-ins, Postgres, MongoDB, Docker.

Programs: MS Excel, Intellij Idea, Aspen Plus.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, 2018 - 2019)

+ ANSEP. Astrocyte Neuron Simulation Environment Platform. Development. Web platform for the analysis of genome-scale metabolic reconstruction related to the study of neurodegenerative diseases. Developed on Python, R, Django and React.js. Build on Docker.

Software Engineer (Software Colombia SAS, 2015 - 2018)

- + SCmail. Architecture, development, and maintenance. Massive email marketing platform. Developed on Java, Spring Framework (Boot, Data JPA, Security and Integration), Amazon Web Services (S3, DynamoDB, Lambda, SES, Autoscale, CodeDeploy, Kinesis, EC2, SQS, SNS and STS), Nodejs and Gradle.
- + SCmail upClient. Architecture, development, and support. Desktop application for the upload of directories/files from the client computer to a repository on Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3). Developed on Java and JavaFX.
- + Elogic Monitor. Architecture, development, and support. Desktop application for the generation of digital signatures, encryption, and files upload, it can be invoked from all web browsers. Developed on Java and JavaFX.
- + Edocument. Development. Document management system created to supply the need of encryption operations and digital signature and requiring ensure authenticity during document flows. Based on Nuxeo (Java EE).

Academic projects (2017-2019)

- + Rescurves. Development, architecture. Open source MS Excel Add-in aimed to ease the three-dimensional plotting of residue curves maps for quaternary systems. Developed on C#.
- + Master's final work: CAMD. Development, architecture. Desktop application to solve the Computer Aided Molecular Design (CAMD) problem of finding the most suitable solvent for a liquid-liquid separation. It makes use of multi-objective optimization and databases mining algorithms. Developed on Java.

Freelancer (Fall 2016)

+ Traveloso. Development, architecture. Web and mobile applications intended to monitoring drivers via one mobile application. Traveloso is a mobile application developed with Ionic and Spring Boot.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

2016 - present	M. Eng. in Systems Engineering and Computing
	Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)
2009 - 2015	Exchange Student for the MSc in Advanced Catalysis and Molecular Modelling
	Universitat de Girona (Spain)
2009 - 2015	Bachelor's degree in Chemical Engineering
	Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)